foreign
[Music]
vestment.in we help individual investors
like you to take right financial and
investment decisions and also to help
you reach your financial goals faster
and smarter let us see how to surrender
or cancel your ICICI Prudential life
insurance policy detailing in this video
now let us see why policyholders might
want to cancel their policies later on
number one the premium might be the
right fit for them when they first
entered the policy but after paying the
premium amount for the one or two terms
they might find it a little high
number two they might feel that the
policy they have purchased is not that
beneficial as they might have believed
in the first place
third they might have bought the policy
under the suggestion of close friend or
relative rather than their own decision
number four they might have a better
policy in mind now which might be
offering them better returns than the
policy they are currently in
but overall the main reason for
canceling the policies always not
understanding the plan in detail
now let us see how to cancel your ICICI
Pro insurance policy we have something
called a free look period a free look
period is nothing but from the date of
purchase the next 15 days that time
period alone is called a free Loop
period if you are not satisfied with the
terms and conditions of the policy you
can cancel your policy within the next
15 days of the date of purchase
the company will terminate the policy
and then refund your premium deposited
within the 10 days after you cancel the
policy
but if the policy was brought through
telemarketing or online the free look
period for you would be extended to 30
days how to cancel your policy within
the free look period is to fill up the
cancellation form for which we have
given a link in the description or to
visit any of the policy uh branches with
your policy document
now if you want to know if there will
any direction of charges from your uh
from the premium they would refund you
then yes
some amount would be uh deducted from
the premium they would refund you for
example if you have purchased a eulog
policy the company will deduct nav
fluctuations stamp Duty charges and any
expenses they bought for you by
conducting medical tests for you
otherwise if you have bought just a
simple term or endowment policy then the
company will deduct a proportionate risk
premium charges stamp Duty charges and
any expenses they want for you by
conducting medical tests for you they
will deduct these charges and then they
will refund the premium to you
have you ever felt like you haven't
missold a policy a Miss selling is
nothing but a relationship manager or a
insurance agent trying to sell your
policy by hiding the false of the policy
and only highlighting the good parts of
the policy by withholding the true
information from you they if they had
sold the positive then that's called
misselling if you feel like something
like that has happened to you and you
want to address it you can go to the
company's uh office and contact the
grievance re Russell officer who will
definitely help you with your issue but
if you don't feel the satisfaction
of what solution they are offering to
you or if you feel like you had no
response from them then you can raise
your complaint to the irda by
approaching them you only need to uh
show them the evidence related to miss
selling and the policy documents for you
to raise a complaint uh you can approach
the irdi by the link we have which we
have shared in the screen also in the
description
what if you feel like you have not been
misold a policy and your free look
period is already over but you still
want to cancel your policy no worries it
is called surrender if you want to
cancel a policy before its maturity and
also your free look period is already
over then it means surrender every
insurance policy has a specific amount
of time allocated for a lock-in period
when the lock-in period is over you can
freely surrender your policy when you
are surrendering your policy a pulse
your policy value will be paid to you
based on your surrender value now let us
see what documents you require for
surrendering your policy first you need
your surrender form which you can
download from the company's website for
which we have given the link in the
description please check it out and you
can download the form by
clicking entering your policy number and
date of birth and then you need your
policy document and also any ID proof
along with your signature assigned copy
of your ID proof plus your canceled
check it's important that your cancel
check has your bank details in them if
you have all these documents then your
uh then you can easily start your
surrendering process
now let us see the reasons for why you
should consider surrendering your policy
by canceling your policy early on you
can actually save the time value of
money because in the next 20 to 25 years
the returns provided by this insurance
policy might not be inflation beating
returns so by canceling this policy now
you might be able to save the time value
of your money
next point is that you cannot expect
more than a four to six percent of
assumed return on your investment in
these types of policy which is not a
better return in the long term and
additionally the return you are getting
will also be
not entirely
four to six percent because Additionally
the GST and additional charges will also
be deducted from the return and be given
to you and next by investing in these
kinds of policies you can miss out on
other better insurance and investment
options like mutual funds and ppf which
give which can give you better returns
than this policy now let us see what are
the four important points you need to
remember when you are purchasing a life
insurance policy
firstly you need to remember the purpose
of your life insurance plan which is to
mitigate Financial uncertainty for your
family in the case of your absence
second a pure term insurance policy can
offer you a higher life cover even at a
lower premium
and thirdly investment can be done
separately from your life insurance
depending upon how much Corpus you
require are at which time timeline and
also depending on your risk appetite
lastly always keep your insurance and
Investments separate and make sure to
invest fully in the product only after
you completely understand what you're
purchasing in the first place if you
find this video useful you can like this
video and also comment on this video
regarding any doubt you have about this
policy so we can try to clarify it for
you also if you have doubts about any
other investment choices or about your
financial course you can always book a
complimentary Financial consultation
with one of a certified financial
planners
uh which for which uh the link is given
in the description and also if you want
to gain knowledge about personal finance
from experts you can register for our
webinars which we regularly conduct
which for which also you can find the
link in the description I hope you
really like this video thank you bye